<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by Ed Beach (Firaxis Games) -->
<GameData>
  <EnglishText>
    <Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY">
      <Text>Secret Society</Text>
    </Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY_DIPLO_NONE_NAME">
			<Text>None</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY_DIPLO_UNKNOWN_NAME">
			<Text>Unknown</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY_DIPLO_UNKNOWN_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>This leader is a member of a Secret Society we have not discovered yet. Once we make contact with it, its members will be revealed.</Text>
		</Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_UNKNOWN_NAME">
      <Text>???</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_UNKNOWN_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>The deeper mysteries have not yet been revealed. We must first demonstrate our commitment.</Text>
    </Row>
		<!--Notifications-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SECRETSOCIETY_LEADER_JOINED_MESSAGE">
			<Text>{1_LeaderOrScreenName} joins {2_SecretSocietyName}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SECRETSOCIETY_LEADER_JOINED_SUMMARY">
			<Text>{1_LeaderOrScreenName} has become a member of the {2_SecretSocietyName}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SECRETSOCIETY_LEVEL_UP_MESSAGE">
			<Text>Secret Society Advances</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_SECRETSOCIETY_LEVEL_UP_SUMMARY">
			<Text>The plan of the {1_SecretSocietyName} advances to its next phase, opening up a more advanced promotion for your Governor contact.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Diplomacy-->
    <Row Tag="LOC_TOOLTIP_SAMPLE_DIPLOMACY_SAME_SECRET_SOCIETY">
      <Text>Member of same Secret Society</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_TOOLTIP_SAMPLE_DIPLOMACY_DIFFERENT_SECRET_SOCIETY">
      <Text>Member of rival Secret Society</Text>
    </Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_LEADER_ANY_REASON_STANDARD_DIPLOMATIC_SAME_SECRET_SOCIETY">
			<Text>I see you by your signs, and I am glad to know that we are kin.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_LEADER_ANY_REASON_STANDARD_DIPLOMATIC_DIFFERENT_SECRET_SOCIETY">
			<Text>On you, I see the mark of evil. Those who know will see your Society for what it is.</Text>
		</Row>
    <!--Alliances-->
    <Row Tag="LOC_ALLIANCE_POINTS_FROM_SOCIETIES">
      <Text>[NEWLINE]{1_Amount} Points from being members of the same secret society</Text>
    </Row>
    <!--Owls of Minerva-->
    <Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY_OWLS_OF_MINERVA_NAME">
      <Text>Owls of Minerva</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY_OWLS_OF_MINERVA_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>The Owls of Minerva are a secret group of high-placed and wealthy individuals. They focus on government, trade, and espionage.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY_OWLS_OF_MINERVA_DISCOVERY">
      <Text>A conversation with a new acquaintance turns to symbols: an eye in a pyramid, a two-headed owl, a serpent biting its own tail. "These are the signs by which we know each other," he says to you. Later, he invites you down through the tunnels below the city to a velvet-draped room filled with figures in cloaks and animal masks, and who you think you recognize as some of the richest and most important people in your empire - and beyond. "Join us," offers a woman in an elaborate moth mask, her voice dripping with wealth and privilege.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY_OWLS_OF_MINERVA_MEMBERSHIP">
      <Text>The rites have been performed. You have recited the names of the founders and their lineages and memorized the signs of the Owls. It is astounding how many there were, all around you, all this time. Your finance minister hides a tattoo of a two-headed owl on his ankle; a silk merchant idly draws an eye on his open palm. Now you are of the Owls.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_OWLS_OF_MINERVA_1_NAME">
      <Text>Initiation</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_OWLS_OF_MINERVA_1_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Unlocked by sending an [ICON_Envoy] Envoy to a City-State. +1 Economic policy slot. Each [ICON_TradeRoute] Trade Route sent to a City-State awards 1 [ICON_Envoy] Envoy there.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_OWLS_OF_MINERVA_2_NAME">
      <Text>Ritual</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_OWLS_OF_MINERVA_2_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Unlocked in Medieval Era. Allows you to construct the Gilded Vault building, a powerful replacement of the Bank.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_OWLS_OF_MINERVA_3_NAME">
      <Text>Indoctrination</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_OWLS_OF_MINERVA_3_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Unlocked in Industrial Era. +1 Wildcard policy slot. +2 Spy capacity. Your cities gain +4 Loyalty per turn and +1 [ICON_Amenities] Amenity when your Spy is in their territory.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_OWLS_OF_MINERVA_4_NAME">
      <Text>Master Plan</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_OWLS_OF_MINERVA_4_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Unlocked in Atomic Era. Every turn, you earn 3% of the [ICON_Gold] Gold in your treasury as income. Whenever an offensive spy mission is successful, you also gain half of the [ICON_Science] Science, [ICON_Culture] Culture, [ICON_Gold] Gold, and [ICON_Faith] Faith that the targeted city earned that turn.</Text>
    </Row>
    <!--Hermetic Order-->
    <Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY_HERMETIC_ORDER_NAME">
      <Text>Hermetic Order</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY_HERMETIC_ORDER_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>The Hermetic Order is a society of unorthodox scientists and alchemists. Their work focuses on science, great people, and resources.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY_HERMETIC_ORDER_DISCOVERY">
      <Text>A wandering mystic appears at your palace. His body is covered in writing of a kind that you have never seen before; the symbols even seem to shine of their own accord. He begins to lecture your courtiers about the hidden alchemical properties of matter: about how mercury can be induced to flow towards the sound of birdsong, how elemental sulfur can be rendered out of sacred texts, and about the hidden resonance of certain stones in moonlight. He asks you, "do you, too, seek to know the true nature of things?"</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY_HERMETIC_ORDER_MEMBERSHIP">
      <Text>Much that was hidden to you is now revealed. Matter is vibrant: metal and stone thrum with secret influences, starlight can be focused to illuminate essential fluids, and the earth itself pulses with energy and light. An entire wing of the palace is a bustle of alchemical activity, and you have learned to live with the occasional explosion.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_HERMETIC_ORDER_1_NAME">
      <Text>Initiation</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_HERMETIC_ORDER_1_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Unlocked by discovering a Natural Wonder. Reveals the Ley Line resource on the map. Ley Lines give a standard adjacency bonus to all specialty districts.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_HERMETIC_ORDER_2_NAME">
      <Text>Ritual</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_HERMETIC_ORDER_2_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Unlocked in Medieval Era. Allows you to construct the Alchemical Society building, a powerful replacement of the University.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_HERMETIC_ORDER_3_NAME">
      <Text>Indoctrination</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_HERMETIC_ORDER_3_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Unlocked in Industrial Era. For every [ICON_GreatPerson] Great Person earned Ley Lines receive +1 yield equal to that [ICON_GreatPerson] Great Person's district type. [ICON_GreatAdmiral] Great Admirals and [ICON_GreatGeneral] Great Generals earn +1 [ICON_Science] Science.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_HERMETIC_ORDER_4_NAME">
      <Text>Master Plan</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_HERMETIC_ORDER_4_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Unlocked in Atomic Era. Unlocks Occult Research, a city project that provides [ICON_GOLD] Gold while active. When completed, it grants [ICON_GreatPerson] Great People points, and [ICON_SCIENCE] Science for every Ley Line in the city.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_LEY_LINE_CULTURE">
      <Text>+{1_num} [ICON_Culture] Culture from the adjacent Ley Line resources.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_LEY_LINE_FAITH">
      <Text>+{1_num} [ICON_Faith] Faith from the adjacent Ley Line resources.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_LEY_LINE_GOLD">
      <Text>+{1_num} [ICON_Gold] Gold from the adjacent Ley Line resources.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_LEY_LINE_PRODUCTION">
      <Text>+{1_num} [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production from the adjacent Ley Line resources.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_DISTRICT_LEY_LINE_SCIENCE">
      <Text>+{1_num} [ICON_Science] Science from the adjacent Ley Line resources.</Text>
    </Row>
    <!--Voidsingers-->
    <Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY_VOIDSINGERS_NAME">
      <Text>Voidsingers</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY_VOIDSINGERS_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>The Voidsingers are a nihilistic cult of dark elder gods. They focus on religion, relics, and (dis)loyalty.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY_VOIDSINGERS_DISCOVERY">
      <Text>It started with a dream of the sea. The waves surged towards the shore but refused to break upon the sand, the water’s surface having been turned to something more like skin. A vast dark shape moved underneath, its form constantly growing new limbs and resorbing old ones. On the wind, there was a song that whispered to you its name, a set of syllables not designed for human tongues. The next day, in the market, you overhear a young urchin with a hollow stare mutter something in this same language.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY_VOIDSINGERS_MEMBERSHIP">
      <Text>Our world is shallow - theirs is deep. You have opened your mind to the song of the void and accepted its truth. The Old Ones are sleeping, but we can hear their dreams. What seems to be madness is a higher truth. We wait and watch the sea and sing their praises.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_VOIDSINGERS_1_NAME">
      <Text>Initiation</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_VOIDSINGERS_1_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Unlocked by discovering a Tribal Village. Allows you to construct the Old God Obelisk building, a powerful replacement of the Monument.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_VOIDSINGERS_2_NAME">
      <Text>Ritual</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_VOIDSINGERS_2_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Unlocked in Medieval Era. Cities earn [ICON_Gold] Gold, [ICON_Science] Science, and [ICON_Culture] Culture per turn equal to 20% of their [ICON_Faith] Faith per turn rate.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_VOIDSINGERS_3_NAME">
      <Text>Indoctrination</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_VOIDSINGERS_3_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Unlocked in Industrial Era. Unlocks the Cultist unit. This unit is purchased with [ICON_Faith] Faith, and uses charges to reduce Loyalty in foreign cities and generate [ICON_GreatWork_Relic] Relics of the Void.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_VOIDSINGERS_4_NAME">
      <Text>Master Plan</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_VOIDSINGERS_4_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Unlocked in Atomic Era. Unlocks Dark Summoning, a city project that provides lots of [ICON_Faith] Faith while active, and upon completion raises the amount of Loyalty damage done by Cultists.</Text>
    </Row>
    <!--Sanguine Pact-->
    <Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY_SANGUINE_PACT_NAME">
      <Text>Sanguine Pact</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY_SANGUINE_PACT_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>The Sanguine Pact share an unhealthy appetite for blood. They focus on building a strong military.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY_SANGUINE_PACT_DISCOVERY">
      <Text>The girl shows up at the gates of the city, white-faced and mumbling about a dark stranger she met on the road, a rush of wind and wings, and the sweetest pain that she ever felt. Your doctors treat her, but she seems to be fading fast. As night falls, a foreign noblewoman (she seems like a noblewoman, at least, just as she seems foreign) appears at your gates. "The girl is with me," she says, her smile revealing astonishingly white – and prominent - teeth. "Perhaps you could invite me in?"</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_SECRETSOCIETY_SANGUINE_PACT_MEMBERSHIP">
      <Text>You have drunk of the red cup and felt new life course through your veins. The night seems alive with new possibilities, and appetites. Your palace stands shuttered and quiet during the day, and but after sunset new courtiers pace the halls, their feet making no sound as they go.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_SANGUINE_PACT_1_NAME">
      <Text>Initiation</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_SANGUINE_PACT_1_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Unlocked by destroying a Barbarian Camp. Grants a Vampire unit in your [ICON_Capital] Capital.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_SANGUINE_PACT_2_NAME">
      <Text>Ritual</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_SANGUINE_PACT_2_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Unlocked in Medieval Era. Grants a Vampire unit in your [ICON_Capital] Capital, and allows your Vampires to construct Vampire Castles (maximum two per empire).</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_SANGUINE_PACT_3_NAME">
      <Text>Indoctrination</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_SANGUINE_PACT_3_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Unlocked in Industrial Era. Grants a Vampire unit in your [ICON_Capital] Capital. Increases maximum Vampire Castle builds to three. Your Vampires now Intimidate adjacent enemy units, reducing their [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength by 5. Pillaging now costs Vampires 1 [ICON_Movement] Movement.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_SANGUINE_PACT_4_NAME">
      <Text>Master Plan</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GOVERNOR_PROMOTION_SANGUINE_PACT_4_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Unlocked in Atomic Era. Grants a Vampire unit in your [ICON_Capital] Capital. Increases maximum Vampire Castle builds to four. Units within one tile of your Vampire Castles may now Airlift to any other tile near one of your Vampire Castles.</Text>
    </Row>
    <!--Buildings-->
    <Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_ALCHEMICAL_SOCIETY_NAME">
      <Text>Alchemical Society</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_ALCHEMICAL_SOCIETY_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Unique to the Hermetic Order, replaces the University. This Campus district generates [ICON_Gold] Gold equal to its [ICON_Science] Science adjacency bonus.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_GILDED_VAULT_NAME">
      <Text>Gilded Vault</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_GILDED_VAULT_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Unique to the Owls of Minerva, replaces the Bank. This Commercial Hub generates [ICON_CULTURE] Culture equal to its [ICON_Gold] Gold adjacency bonus.  Having a Harbor in this city provides you with +1 [ICON_TradeRoute] Trade Route capacity.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_OLD_GOD_OBELISK_NAME">
      <Text>Old God Obelisk</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_OLD_GOD_OBELISK_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Unique to the Voidsingers, replaces the Monument. Contains 1 Great Work slot that can hold any type of Great Work. Provides +1 Loyalty per turn in this city. If the city already has maximum Loyalty, also provides an additional +1 [ICON_Culture] Culture.</Text>
    </Row>
    <!--Improvements-->
    <Row Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_NAME">
      <Text>Vampire Castle</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_IMPROVEMENT_VAMPIRE_CASTLE_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Can be built in player-owned and neutral territory by a Vampire. Provides Fortification to units on the tile. Duplicates yields from adjacent tiles when built, adds them to the Vampire Castle's tile, and grants the tile's yield to the [ICON_Capital] Capital city.</Text>
    </Row>
    <!--Resources-->
    <Row Tag="LOC_RESOURCE_LEY_LINE_NAME">
      <Text>Ley Line</Text>
    </Row>
    <!--Units-->
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_VAMPIRE_NAME">
      <Text>Vampire</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_VAMPIRE_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Combat unit unique to the Sanguine Pact. Has base [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength equal to the strongest unit your cities have produced. Gains permanent [ICON_Strength] Combat Strength when units die in adjacent tiles.  Strength from Barbarian deaths is capped at +10. When killed, retreats with 1 HP to the [ICON_Capital] Capital or nearest Vampire Castle. Heals an additional 50 HP from pillaging enemy tiles, but receives reduced passive healing.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_CULTIST_NAME">
      <Text>Cultist</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNIT_CULTIST_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Support unit unique to the Voidsingers. Once it dies or loses all charges, its devoted sacrifice awards the player a [ICON_GreatWork_Relic] Relic of the Void. Can move into foreign lands when not at war, and use a charge to Recruit Followers in an adjacent foreign city, causing it to lose 10 Loyalty.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_ABILITY_SPREAD_DISSENT_NAME">
      <Text>Recruit Followers</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_ABILITY_SPREAD_DISSENT_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Can Recruit Followers in an adjacent enemy city, causing it to lose 10 Loyalty. Once the Dark Summoning city project is unlocked, this action deals 1 more Loyalty damage per project completed, up to a maximum total of 30.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPREAD_DISSENT_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Recruit Followers</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITCOMMAND_SPREAD_DISSENT_FAILURE_REQUIRES_ENEMY_CITY">
      <Text>Must be adjacent to an enemy City Center</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_ABILITY_CULTIST_RELIC_ON_DEATH_NAME">
      <Text>Sacrifice</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_ABILITY_CULTIST_RELIC_ON_DEATH_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Once it dies or loses all charges, owner is given a [ICON_GreatWork_Relic] Relic of the Void.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_ABILITY_CULTIST_ENTER_FOREIGN_LANDS_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Can enter foreign lands when not at war.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="SANGUINE_PACT_VAMPIRE_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESC">
      <Text>+{Property} from units that have died near the Vampire</Text>
    </Row>
		<Row Tag="SANGUINE_PACT_VAMPIRE_BARB_COMBAT_STRENGTH_DESC">
			<Text>+{Property} from barbarians that have died near the Vampire</Text>
		</Row>
    <Row Tag="SANGUINE_PACT_VAMPIRE_INIMIDATE_DESC">
      <Text>{1_Amount} from a nearby Vampire</Text>
    </Row>
	<!--Notifications -->
	<!--Change "Holy Relic" to "Relic" for Secret Societies mode, as our new relics in this mode aren't holy -->
	<Replace Tag="LOC_NOTIFICATION_RELIC_CREATED_SUMMARY">
		<Text>The [ICON_GreatWork_Relic] Relic {1_RelicName} has been placed in the {2_BuildingName} in {3_CityName}.</Text>
	</Replace>
    <!--Projects-->
    <Row Tag="LOC_PROJECT_OCCULT_RESEARCH_NAME">
      <Text>Occult Research</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_PROJECT_OCCULT_RESEARCH_SHORT_NAME">
      <Text>Occult Research</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_PROJECT_OCCULT_RESEARCH_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Project that provides [ICON_Gold] Gold every turn. Receive [ICON_SCIENCE] Science per Ley Line in this city and [ICON_GreatScientist] Great Scientist, [ICON_GreatMerchant] Great Merchant, and  [ICON_GreatEngineer] Great Engineer points once finished. This project requires a Campus district.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_PROJECT_DARK_SUMMONING_NAME">
      <Text>Dark Summoning</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_PROJECT_DARK_SUMMONING_SHORT_NAME">
      <Text>Dark Summoning</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_PROJECT_DARK_SUMMONING_DESCRIPTION">
      <Text>Project that provides lots of [ICON_Faith] Faith every turn. Upon completion it increases the amount of Loyalty damage done by Cultists by 2 (up to a maximum of 30). This project Requires an Old God Obelisk building.</Text>
    </Row>
	<!--Secret Society Popup-->
    <Row Tag="LOC_DISCOVERED_SOCIETY">
      <Text>Discovered a Society!</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_DISCOVERED_SOCIETY_DESC">
      <Text>You have discovered a mysterious society called the {1_SocietyName}, and earned 1 [Icon_Governor] Governor Title.</Text>
    </Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DISCOVERED_SOCIETY_WHILE_MEMBER_OF_ANOTHER">
			<Text>The man in the shadows beckons to you, offering to show you the wonders of the {1_SocietyName}. Too late, he sees your knowing grin, and recognizes you as a member of the {2_MemberSocietyName}. In his folly, he had let slip the secret signs by which his group knows its members, and you can recognize them on sight.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The {2_MemberSocietyName} rewards your loyalty, and you can use the [Icon_Governor] Governor Title as you see fit.</Text>
		</Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_JOINED_SOCIETY">
      <Text>Joined a Society!</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_JOINED_SOCIETY_DESC">
      <Text>You have joined a society called the {1_SocietyName}.</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GO_TO_GOVERNORS">
      <Text>Go To Governors Screen</Text>
    </Row>
    <!--Relics of the Void-->
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_1_NAME">
      <Text>Relic of the Devouring Angel</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_2_NAME">
      <Text>Fungal Spore</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_3_NAME">
      <Text>Fragment of Akkorokamui</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_4_NAME">
      <Text>Black Goat's Horn</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_5_NAME">
      <Text>Foundation Stone</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_6_NAME">
      <Text>Relic of the Sightless Worm</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_7_NAME">
      <Text>Shard of Yog-Sothoth</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_8_NAME">
      <Text>Child of Azathoth</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_9_NAME">
      <Text>Chorus of the Drowned</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_10_NAME">
      <Text>Vessel of Nyarlathotep</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_11_NAME">
      <Text>Rangda's Chalice</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_12_NAME">
      <Text>Cup of the Star-Spawn</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_13_NAME">
      <Text>The Singing Worm</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_14_NAME">
      <Text>The Dream-Eater</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_15_NAME">
      <Text>The Shrieking Flowers</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_16_NAME">
      <Text>The Loveless Ones</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_17_NAME">
      <Text>The Tome of Dagon</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_18_NAME">
      <Text>The Book of Dead Names</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_19_NAME">
      <Text>The Left-Hand Sutra</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_20_NAME">
      <Text>Instructions for the Kumanthong</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_21_NAME">
      <Text>Teachings of the Worm</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_22_NAME">
      <Text>Memoirs of a Blind Astronomer</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_23_NAME">
      <Text>A Journal of Next Year's Dreams</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_24_NAME">
      <Text>Chronicle of Descent</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_GREATWORK_VOIDSIGNERS_RELIC_25_NAME">
      <Text>Hint Guide: Civilization II</Text>
    </Row>
    <!--Vampire Names-->
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_CARMILLA">
      <Text>Carmilla</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_CHRISTABEL">
      <Text>Christabel</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_COUNT">
      <Text>Count</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_VLAD">
      <Text>Vlad</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_LENORE">
      <Text>Lenore</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_LORD">
      <Text>Lord</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_ONEIZA">
      <Text>Oneiza</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_LUDMILLA">
      <Text>Ludmilla</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_SAVA">
      <Text>Sava</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_BARON">
      <Text>Baron</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_LODIN">
      <Text>Lodin</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_LADY">
      <Text>Lady</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_MARQUIS">
      <Text>Marquis</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_COUNTESS">
      <Text>Countess</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_PETAR">
      <Text>Petar</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_DUKE">
      <Text>Duke</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_GRAF">
      <Text>Graf</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_DOM">
      <Text>Dom</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_MASTER">
      <Text>Master</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_VOIVODE">
      <Text>Voivode</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_BARONESS">
      <Text>Baroness</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_WOLFGANG">
      <Text>Wolfgang</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_BOYAR">
      <Text>Boyar</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_SHERIDAN">
      <Text>Sheridan</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_PREFIX_DUCHESS">
      <Text>Duchess</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_LE_FANU">
      <Text>Le Fanu</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_COLERIDGE">
      <Text>Coleridge</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_VARNEY">
      <Text>Varney</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_TEPES">
      <Text>Tepes</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_RUTHVEN">
      <Text>Ruthven</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_WESTERNA">
      <Text>Westenra</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_ORLOK">
      <Text>Orlok</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_BATHORY">
      <Text>Bathory</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_SAVANOVIK">
      <Text>Savanovik</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_ZAROVICH">
      <Text>Zarovich</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_KROV">
      <Text>Krov</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_VON_TOD">
      <Text>Von Tod</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_HARKER">
      <Text>Harker</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_DAVOVICH">
      <Text>Davovich</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_BLAGOJEVIC">
      <Text>Blagojevic</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_PEUCHEN">
      <Text>Peuchen</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_KRASEU">
      <Text>Kraseu</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_VOLTAIRE">
      <Text>Voltaire</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_ALLATIUS">
      <Text>Allatius</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_KIKUCHI">
      <Text>Kikuchi</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_LAMORTE">
      <Text>Lamorte</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_LANOCHE">
      <Text>Lanoche</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_STOKER">
      <Text>Stoker</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_BYRON">
      <Text>Byron</Text>
    </Row>
    <Row Tag="LOC_UNITNAME_SUFFIX_SHELLEY">
      <Text>Shelley</Text>
    </Row>
    <!-- Diplomatic texts -->
    <Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_REASON_FROM_AI_LEADER_ANY_REASON_STANDARD_DIPLOMATIC_DIFFERENT_SECRET_SOCIETY">
      <Text>(You belong to different secret societies.)</Text>
    </Row>
  </EnglishText>
</GameData>
