<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
	<EnglishText>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MENELIK_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY">
			<Text>Menelik founds cities on the hills, focusing on [ICON_Faith] Faith and letting his Council of Ministers boost his [ICON_Science] Science and [ICON_Culture] Culture with an eye towards a Religious or Culture Victory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MENELIK_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY">
			<Text>Menelik’s focus is on a defensive, religious and culture-based game. Ethiopia’s advantages come into play by settling the hills: the Council of Ministers gives Ethiopia a bonus to [ICON_Science] Science and [ICON_Culture] Culture equal to 15% of [ICON_Faith] Faith production in hill-based cities, and Menelik can build Rock-Hewn Churches on hills, further boosting his [ICON_Faith] Faith. To protect his highland monasteries, Menelik has the Oromo Cavalry, a mid-game unit that moves without penalties in the hills. Here Menelik can make sure that Ethiopian cities remain free – and remain powerhouses of [ICON_Faith] Faith. Later in the game, Menelik can use this Faith to purchase Archaeologists, making his best strategy a Religious or Culture Victory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- civs -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_ETHIOPIA_LOCATION">
			<Text>East Africa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_ETHIOPIA_SIZE">
			<Text>Est. 426 thousand square miles (1.1 million square km)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_ETHIOPIA_POPULATION">
			<Text>Est. 108 million</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_CIVINFO_ETHIOPIA_CAPITAL">
			<Text>Addis Ababa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_ETHIOPIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Our ancestors evolved in East Africa, and “Lucy,” that three-million-year-old hominid discovered in 1974, lived in the Awash valley. So it is fair to say that few regions can boast a longer (pre)history than Ethiopia. The country has been the crossroads of human evolution, the spread of Christianity, and the end of colonialism, and has played a decisive role in each.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_ETHIOPIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>To the east of Ethiopia lies the Red Sea (and, beyond that, the Arabian Peninsula and Mesopotamia), and to the west, the Nile River. With such proximity to the earliest of human civilizations, it is no surprise that a kingdom, “Punt,” rose as a wealthy trading post in Ethiopia in early antiquity. Punt produced and exported valuables such as gold, myrrh, frankincense, ebony, and ivory – valuables that earned the kingdom the name “God’s Land” amongst Egyptian traders. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_ETHIOPIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>A series of independent kingdoms followed. Of these, Axum became one of the most powerful polities around the 1st century BC, spanning the Red Sea to southern Arabia and extending inland to the Nile valley in what is now Sudan. For the next few centuries, while Egypt fell to Rome, Axum prospered. The kingdom lay at a trade crossroads, dealing in gorgeous dyes, iron for making weapons, and glassware – a Roman account devotes a page just to listing all the different goods one could trade in Axum, with networks as far as India.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_ETHIOPIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>In the 4th century AD, Christianity was introduced to Axum, making it one of the first Christian kingdoms in the world (just after Armenia, but before Rome). Byzantine (Eastern Roman Empire) historians describe how the king captured a Syrian Christian and then, in the process of long conversations with his captive, became a Christian himself. While royal coins were subsequently emblazoned with a cross, the religion did not permeate the entire kingdom, staying a religion of the elite (unlike in Rome, where Christianity was more associated with commoners). But during one of the purges of Christians from Rome, many Christian holy men sought refuge in Ethiopia, and gradually converted much of the populace (traditional religions as well as Judaism persisted, and persist to this day). At this time, too, a group known as the Nine Saints came to Axum and translated the Bible from Greek into Ge’ez, the local language and established a monastic order. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_ETHIOPIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
			<Text>But power shifts. Rome fell, Muslim rulers came to dominate the Red Sea region, and Axum’s own subjects over-worked fragile arid land. Ethiopian power drifted southward and turned inwards.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_ETHIOPIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6">
			<Text>All was not lost during this moment of isolation. The traditions established by the Nine Saints continued and are preserved in the time-frozen churches of Lalibela, constructed during the Zagwe dynasty (900s-1200s). They remain an established World Heritage site today and still see active visits by pilgrims. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_ETHIOPIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7">
			<Text>Ethiopia was not to remain dormant forever. A new emperor, Yekuno Amlak eliminated the last of the Zagwe kings and, to solidify his rule, married one of those king’s daughters. In addition, he spread a legend to help shore up his legitimacy, claiming to be the descendant of the ancient king Solomon and the Queen of Sheba —hence the name of this new dynasty, the Solomonic dynasty.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_ETHIOPIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8">
			<Text>Under the Solomonic dynasty, Ethiopia started to ascend once more, climbing out from its historical dark age. Although they still lacked a fixed capital (the empire moved around in mobile camps), the empire progressed in other ways. They achieved military success and controlled most of the Horn of Africa. The religious fervor of the region remained, and facilitated contact with European powers, particularly during the late 1400s through the early 1500s. Artists and writers also flourished during this time and created great works, including the epic, Kebra Nagast, a Ge’ez epic that retells the story of the Queen of Sheba, her relationship with King Solomon, and how the Ark of the Covenant was brought to Ethiopia with their son, Menelik.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_ETHIOPIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_9">
			<Text>Unfortunately, the mid-1500s brought conflict to Ethiopia. The Abyssinian-Adal War between Christian Ethiopia (Abyssinia) and Muslim Somalia (Adal) lasted from 1528 to 1543 AD, leaving Ethiopia in a bloody and drastically weakened state. Churches and manuscripts burned, and many lives were lost in the fighting. The Ethiopian Emperor Lebna Dengel reached out to Portugal, who responded by sending a fleet complete with musketeers to Massawa in 1541. Even with the aid of the Portuguese fleet, Ethiopia still had trouble fending off “the Conqueror” Ahmad ibn Ibrahim al-Ghazi. Emperor Galawdewos joined with the surviving Portuguese forces and marched west to confront the Conqueror once again. Al-Ghazi was finally defeated in the Battle of Wayna Daga, and his armies retreated from Ethiopia. Skirmishes continued, however, through 1559 until Galawdewos foolishly attacked the city of Harar with a skeleton force. He was executed, leaving the monarchy devastated. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_ETHIOPIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_10">
			<Text>A permanent capital wouldn’t be established again until 1636. The founding of Gonder helped bring consistency back to Ethiopia (even if it also brought court turmoil that led to Shakespearean levels of political intrigue and drama). It again became the center of trade, and Gonder was able to build a substantial infrastructure. The Ethiopian nobility built new palaces and beautiful gardens, drawing in philosophers and artists once again.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_ETHIOPIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_11">
			<Text>By the late 1800s, Gonder declined, leaving behind a medley of combative provinces. Three emperors worked to unite Ethiopia during their respective times. Emperor Tewodros II went from being a chief’s son, to a local monastery to be educated, to eventually become the leader of a group of bandits. He was a smart leader and capable warrior, which gained him followers until his group of bandits became the size of a small army. He became so well known, that to try and appease him, Empress Menen Liben Amede arranged a marriage between him and her granddaughter. For a while, this worked, until Tewodros decided he was done with his new relatives and wanted more power. He took over and through conquest, unified a large portion of the region. He wasn’t without some compassion, though. He took in the son of a prince he killed and eventually married that boy to his daughter Alitash. The boy, now a young man, escaped Tewodros and went on to become Emperor Menelik II, who cemented Ethiopia’s fame as a bastion against colonialism.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_ETHIOPIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_12">
			<Text>Colonialism had spread like a fever throughout Europe, and those powers late to the game - Italy, specifically - sought their own chance to build an empire. In Ethiopia’s region, the Ottoman Empire had reigned for years. But, through force and cunning, the English had managed to gain control over Egypt, and the French over Somalia. A strip of land on the Red Sea between British and French dominions – what is today Eritrea – became a vital beachhead into the African highlands, and the English, fearing French domination and not trusting Ethiopian rule, “gave” it to the Italians. Thus began the first Italo-Ethiopian War. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_ETHIOPIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_13">
			<Text>It did not end well for the Europeans. Vastly outnumbered and fighting far from their home turf, the Italians were slaughtered and returned home in defeat. And, suddenly, the world heard about an African ruler who dared to stand up to Europe, and who won. The Italians were to strike again, just before World War II, and were this time victorious. Like Menelik, the emperor who stood up to them, Haile Selassie – born Ras Tafari Makonnen (yes, the “Ras Tafari” that present-day Rastafarians identify with) became famous as a hero who stood up to European domination. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_PAGE_CIVILIZATION_ETHIOPIA_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_14">
			<Text>Today, Ethiopia is a populous country in East Africa. Like many other countries in Africa, it faced division and bloodshed in the Cold War, and the line of Solomon fell to a Communist coup in 1974. In the 1990s, facing the fall of the Soviet Union and the independence of Eritrea (the former Italian colony, and Ethiopia’s Red Sea port), Ethiopia has again warmed to the West. </Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- leaders -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MENELIK_TITLE">
			<Text>Menelik II</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MENELIK_QUOTE">
			<Text>If powers at a distance come forward to partition Africa between them, I do not intend to be an indifferent spectator.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MENELIK_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>It takes a good man to learn from his friends and a greater man to learn from his enemies. Menelik II, then Sahle Miriam, was born on August 17, 1844, in Shewa, Ethiopia. Menelik was still just a child when Emperor Tewodros II invaded the Shewan region and killed his father, Prince Haile-Melekot. Rather than ending Haile-Melekot’s line and killing a potential threat to his rule, the Emperor Tewodros decided to take the young boy into his court in Magdala. Miriam was by no means free—he was a political hostage. However, Tewodros didn’t relegate Miriam to some distant tower. Tewodros raised Miriam with his alongside his children and treated him well. Miriam learned what he could during this time from Tewodros, ultimately coming to understand and even share Tewodros’s hope for a unified Ethiopia. However, Miriam still wanted to be free, and in 1865, he fled the court with the help of other Shewan hostages.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MENELIK_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>The current governor of Shewa fled when Miriam arrived home, and the returning prince assumed the throne with little resistance, becoming King of the Shewa. He wasn’t willing to settle for just Shewa, though. Miriam watched Tewodros, and waited. Even when Emperor Tewodros died in 1868, Miriam remained patient. Miriam knew he would need support if he wanted to become the next Emperor. He also needed allies if he wanted to see his dream of a modernized and unified Ethiopia come to fruition. With that in mind, Miriam made connections between Shewa and nearby kingdoms. When the Emperor Yohannes, caught between expansionist Europeans in Egypt to the north, and a religious fundamentalist movement in Sudan, to the West, fell in battle, Miriam knew it was time. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MENELIK_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
			<Text>Miriam took the title of Emperor and assumed the name of Emperor Menelik II on November 3, 1889. He drew inspiration for his new name from Menelik I, the son of Solomon and the Queen of Sheba. Under this name, he planned to make his reign a long one filled with prosperity for the people of Ethiopia.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MENELIK_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_4">
			<Text>One of Menelik’s first challenges as Emperor was the encroachment of the Italians, who had been, in a bit of double-dealing on the English part, “given” the Red Sea coast (the English wanted a buffer between their newly-acquired Egypt and French Somalia). Menelik negotiated with the Italians, signing the Treaty of Wichale. The treaty was intended only to give the newly established colony of Eritrea to Italy; however, it was misinterpreted to allow the Italians the right to claim Ethiopia. Menelik tried to resolve the issue peacefully, but he was ultimately forced to reject the treaty and defend Ethiopia’s land. Several skirmishes and one major battle at Adwa later, Menelik and Ethiopia stood victorious. With this victory, he negotiated the Treaty of Addis Ababa, which further established that Ethiopia was independent. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MENELIK_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_5">
			<Text>The Battle of Adwa was a turning point in world history. Before, European countries had thought of themselves as superior to nearly everywhere else in the world. But now, an African nation had successfully defended itself against a European one. With this success, colonized people in Africa, Asia, and the Americas took notice. Colonialism was not long for the world. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MENELIK_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_6">
			<Text>Following the treaty, Menelik moved to start modernizing Ethiopia and establishing it as a powerful nation with its own identity. He built the capital of Addis Ababa and created a national currency. Menelik further worked to develop a national infrastructure by building schools and making travel more accessible and comfortable through the creation of railways. He also made sure that people could remain in contact through a postal and telegraph system. Menelik wanted his country to prosper and grow both metaphorically and literally. He expanded his borders to almost the same size as the current ones thanks to his previous coalitions. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MENELIK_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_7">
			<Text>There were still voices, however, that Menelik knew weren’t being heard, and he was determined to make sure their words were spoken. He actively worked to suppress and ultimately destroy the slave trade within Ethiopia. Although previous rulers outlawed the “industry”, Menelik punished slavers with amputation and broke apart slave trading towns. Although he couldn’t change the minds of everyone within his nation, he made sure that the seeds were sown for future generations.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MENELIK_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_8">
			<Text>Menelik married three times both before and during his rule. He left behind his first wife after escaping Emperor Tewodros. It’s uncertain whether either of them was heartbroken over the matter since both married other people soon after. The same year that Menelik “divorced” his first wife, he married Woizero Befana Wolde Michael. Menelik loved her dearly, but he was forced to divorce her after multiple allegations of treason. Despite these allegations, Menelik still professed his love to her until his third and final marriage to Taytu Betul. He remained with her until his death. Taytu proved to be a powerful monarch and was an influential woman even before their marriage.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_MENELIK_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_9">
			<Text>In 1909, Menelik suffered a stroke that left him a shell of his former self. The Empress stepped up to reign in his stead until Ras Bitwaddad Tesemma took over. His rule was short lived, however, and a council was formed to rule until Menelik’s death in 1913. The Empress was, to her chagrin, not invited to voice her opinions within the council. Menelik’s burial was quiet and sudden. There were no announcements, no ceremonies—just the silent passing of one of the most favorably remembered rulers of Ethiopia. His legacy left behind a stable country with an identity that remained even through modernization.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- units -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_ETHIOPIAN_OROMO_CAVALRY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>The word “Oromo” refers to the dominant ethnic group in Ethiopia, making up about a third of the total population. The Oromo at times had their own kingdom, language and religion (although in present-day Ethiopia they are evenly split between Muslims and Christians). During the First Italo-Ethiopian War, when Italy attempted to seize Ethiopia as a colonial possession, the Ethiopian emperor Menelik used Oromo cavalrymen to devastating effect, especially in the decisive Battle of Adwa.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_UNITS_PAGE_UNIT_ETHIOPIAN_OROMO_CAVALRY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>The Oromo cavalry were not true cavalry, but mounted infantrymen, meaning that they did not fire weapons from horseback, but would gallop towards the Italians, dismount, and then fire. With their lion’s-mane headdresses and fierce reputation, they became one of the most feared military units of the era. During the Italian invasion, a rumor spread around the Italian camps that Oromo cavalry (whom the Italians called “Galla” – a word that was seen as offensive by the Oromo) would castrate the bodies of enemies that held weapons – a rumor that caused many Italians to toss aside their guns the moment that the Oromo began their charge. Italian soldiers reported their compatriots turning their guns on themselves rather than facing the Oromo. One report depicts a lone Italian survivor of an Oromo attack, dazed out of his mind, unable to say anything but “Galla cavalry. Galla cavalry. Horror. Horror.” </Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- buildings and districts -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_DISTRICTS_PAGE_DISTRICT_DIPLOMATIC_QUARTER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Meetings of foreign leaders, even in ancient times, do not just involve two people sitting down to talk. Rather, they are accompanied by a vast network of ambassadors, consuls, aides, translators, etc. All these people need a place to work. In Washington D.C., a stretch of Massachusetts Avenue serves as just this sort of place devoted to diplomacy. Lining this street, are sometimes luxurious, sometimes modest, sometimes old and sometimes brand-new buildings sporting the flags of multiple nations. Most nations have such neighborhoods: Seoul’s Itaewon, Beijing’s Chaoyang, Paris’s 7th arrondissement, Abuja’s Independence and Constitution Aves, are just some examples. These are places where foreign leaders come, discuss, and have their representatives. And not just foreigners: diplomatic quarters are also centers for universities’ international schools, think-tanks and lobbying firms, places to eat, drink and entertain… and spy and counterspy.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_BUILDING_CHANCERY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>A collection of consulates and embassies is termed a chancery. Here, diplomats gather to work out treaties and arrange deals… and (more likely than not) rub shoulders with spies. A chancery provides a centralized place to observe and monitor foreign agents within the country, to improve relations (and to try and figure out what other countries might be up to). It is larger and more exhaustive than a consulate.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_BUILDING_CONSULATE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>A consulate refers quite simply to the place of work of a consul – in this meaning, a lesser version of an ambassador and intended to carry out the functions of an embassy on a smaller scale. A country might set up a consulate in New York, for instance, in order to help its citizens who live or visit there, whereas the main embassy might be in Washington, D.C. Here, “consulate” refers not necessarily to this, but to a facility constructed to house foreign dignitaries close to the capital – and close under watch.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- improvements -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ROCK_HEWN_CHURCH_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>In the 11th century, Ethiopian Christians found themselves cut off. Whereas in centuries before, pilgrims from the ancient Christian centers would travel to the Holy Land, but Muslim conquests prevented these travels. King Lalibela, then, decided to construct a site closer to home, something impressive enough to draw pilgrims from the region without them having to travel across a war-torn region. To this end, he ordered the construction of a “New Jerusalem” – the rock-hewn churches of Lalibela.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_ROCK_HEWN_CHURCH_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
			<Text>These were not ordinary churches. Instead, each was carved from a single giant stone, including doors, windows, columns, along with all of the practicalities: drainage ditches, catacombs, and hermits’ caves. As was required by the order to create a “New Jerusalem,” these churches include replicas of Jesus’s birthplace and tomb, so that visiting pilgrims could feel that they were able to commune with God without risking life and limb. They were – and remain - vital places of pilgrimage and worship for Coptic Christians.</Text>
		</Row>
	</EnglishText>
</GameData>
